



Robert Smith Cell 514-555-4470

1555 University Street, Montreal, QC, H3B 1X9

rsmith@expertech.ca

#### **Professional Profile**

- Extensive experience in installation, administration and networking in various environments.
- Thorough knowledge of Windows Vista; Windows XP; Windows 2000 Server; Windows Server 2003; Windows Server 2008; Windows NT; Novell; DOS; OS/2; TCP/IP; InstallShield; Ghost; Deploy Center; Microsoft SMS 2003; and BDD.
- Active Directory Services; Active Directory Group Policy Objects (GPO); Group Policy Management Console (GPMC); DHCP; WINS; and DNS.
- Utilized Install Shield Scripting to package software for application deployment.
- Excellent command of running projects employing industry standard project management techniques.
- Extensive documentation and training experience.
- Successful project and technical team leader and motivator.

Operating Systems: Windows Vista; Windows XP; Windows NT 4.0; Novell NetWare; DOS and OS/2.

Microsoft Servers: Windows 2000 Server: Windows Server 2003: Windows Server 2008: Wi

Windows 2000 Server; Windows Server 2003; Windows Server 2008; Windows Server 2008 Core; AD 2003; AD DS 2008; Microsoft Exchange 2003; Microsoft

Exchange 2007.

Software: MS Office 2007; MS Office 2003/XP; Norton Utilities; WinFax; PC Anywhere;

McAfee; WinZip; Symantec Ghost; Veritas; Heat; Remedy 7.0/6.0; DameWare Mini Remote Console; Email (Microsoft Exchange, Lotus Notes Mail); Oracle and

many others.

Hardware: Intel, 3COM, HP Proliant DL380, HP ML570, IBM x86 Servers, Dell PowerEdge

M805 and others.

**Virtualization**: Microsoft Virtual Server 2005 R2, VMware.

**Networking:** Eicon Communications products such as OSI Gateway for DOS and OS/2; SNA

Gateway; IPX/SPX; TCP/IP; Routers; Switches; Modems; Hubs and Bridges.

#### **Professional Accomplishments**

- MCTS Windows Server 2008 Active Directory Configuration (70-640).
- MCTS Microsoft Windows Vista Client (70-620).
- MCTS Windows Vista and Exchange 2007.
- MCTS Supporting Windows Vista Operating System and Applications (BDD).
- Microsoft Windows Deploying Windows Server 2008 (Course 6418).
- ITIL (Information Technology Infrastructure Library) Foundation Ver. 3.
- MCDST Microsoft Certified Desktop Certified Technician.
- MCP Microsoft Certified Professional.
- Supporting Windows Vista Operating System and Applications.
- Microsoft SMS 2003 Administration & BDD 2003.
- Managing a Microsoft Windows Server 2003 Environment.
- Windows XP, Windows 2000 Professional and Windows NT System Administration.
- MS Project and Project Management Techniques.
- CNA Certified NetWare Administrator and cc:Mail System Administration.

#### **Education**

Bachelor of Commerce 2001

University of Toronto, ON

#### **Professional Experience**

### ExperTech Inc., Montreal Systems Administrator

August 2008 to March 2009

- Responsible for third-level support for all server related issues.
- Participated in complete system builds, upgrades, migrations, code deployments and patch management.
- Implemented security policy and virus protection.
- Administered change management related to server upgrades and software installation.
- Prepared and maintained documentation of technologies, standards and procedures.
- Maintained and supported more than 2000 servers for Intel Steady State.

#### **Proof of Concept (Windows Server 2008 Deployment)**

- Configured Server Core; configured networking; security and system settings on Server Core.
- Added and removed server roles and features; configured AD Domain Services roles; configured network infrastructure roles; configured file and print services; configured IIS7 on Server Core.
- Added backup features and used unattend.xml files to automate Windows Server 2008 setup.
- Performed unattended domain controller installation.

**Technical Environment** – Windows 2000 Server; Windows Server 2003; Windows Server 2008; VMware Server and Tivoli Storage Manager.

**Responsible for**: Day-to-day support on Windows Server and backup/restoration for more than 2000+ Intel Servers; job entailed frequent visit to Data Center, due to the nature of the work.

#### **Assante, Calgary**

Sr. Infrastructure Specialist – Windows Vista & Office 2007 Certification Project July 2007 to June 2008

- Worked on an extensive certification project for Windows Vista and Office 2007 that impacted 22,000+ users for Investors Group.
- Windows Vista Features Performed extensive research on the Windows Vista features and collaborated with the Project Senior Systems Architect to enable/disable features such as Data Synchronization; Desktop Search; Disk Diagnostics; Document Editor; Network Access; Network Communications Protocol; Peer File Sharing; Remote Desktop (RDC+RA); Smart Projector Detection; Vista Gadgets; Windows Meeting Space and Windows Update. Once these features were tested in the computer lab and a consensus decision was reached, I prepared a Detailed Infrastructure Document and the Final Unit Test Plan and sent it to the PM for approval. The Windows Vista Image for the Group was created based on these features.
- BlackBerry® Device, BlackBerry® Desktop, BlackBerry® Enterprise Server (BES), BES Console Upgraded BlackBerry® Enterprise Server (BES) and the Console to BES v.4.1 SP4. Setup a Lab for BES v.4.0 SP7; upgraded them for Office 2007 compatibility, i.e., BES v.4.1 SP4; BES Console v.4.1 SP4. Tested Bloomberg v.1.2 and ACT v.8.0. Once everything was tested and found operable, I prepared a Detailed Infrastructure Document, Unit Test Plan, BlackBerry® Enterprise Server Upgrade Guide; and Play Book (Build Document; Operational Procedures Document and Transition to Production) documents. These documents are an integral part of promoting any applications to the Production Environment. The migration on all Blackberry® Enterprise Servers was handled by the Mail Team, under the Project Team's guidance. All lab setup was done on virtual servers.
- NTI Backup NOW Researched and determined NTI Backup NOW v.4.7.5.8 compatibility to Windows Vista.
  Performed rigorous testing on Vista image and certified it for Vista compatibility. Prepared a Detailed
  Infrastructure Document; Unit Test Plan; Build Document; Operational Procedures Document and Transition
  to Production documents. These documents are an integral part for promoting any applications to the
  Production Environment. NTI Backup NOW is used by more than 5300 Consultants for daily backups.
- Print drivers for network printers; Outlook 2007; IE 7 for Vista and many more.

**Technical Environment** – Windows Vista; Office 2007; Windows Server 2003; Microsoft Virtual Server 2005 R2; BES 4.1 SP4; LANDesk; and BDD.

Responsible for: Certifying all infrastructure applications against Windows Vista, Office 2007.

## **HDS Retail North America, Toronto IT Specialist**

April 2007 to June 2007

- Prepared the environment for deployment of Windows Server 2003.
- Analyzed the hardware and software requirements of Active Directory.
- Installed, configured, and provide troubleshooting for Server 2003.
- Migrated Windows Server 2003 from test environment to the production environment.
- Implemented and managed IP Addressing; configured TCP/IP addressing on a server.
- Created the Forest Root domain, and a Child domain in a production environment.
- Installed and configured an Active Directory Domain Controller.
- Established external trusts and cross-forest trusts.
- Managed an Active Directory site; replication schedules, site links and boundaries, used ADUC to create and manage computer, user and group accounts in an Active Directory environment.
- Used DcDiag, NetDiag techniques for troubleshooting.
- Performed authoritative and non-authoritative restore operations.
- Diagnosed and resolved issues related to masters role failure and AD database.
- Configured automatic updates for network clients by using Group Policy.
- Designed, planned and implemented Group Policy, delegation strategies and OU structure.
- Managed local, roaming, and mandatory profiles, planed strategy for placing Global Catalogue (GC) and evaluated the need to enable Universal Group Caching.
- Created approximately 500 user accounts in Active Directory and migrated all Windows NT users by 'User State Migration Tool (USMT)'.

#### **Canadian Tire, Montreal**

#### Team Lead for Microsoft SMS 2003 & BDD (Windows XP Migration Project)

August 2006 to March 2007

- Migrated more than 5000 IBM personal computers and laptops from Windows NT to Windows XP at Canadian Tire using Microsoft SMS 2003 and Business Desktop Deployment (BDD).
- Served as Team Lead in charge of desktop deployment execution to field offices and corporate locations.
- Provided project training to XP Specialist.
- Participated in project planning, deployment logistics and client profiling/needs analyst.
- Responsible for imaging and deploying IBM T42 Laptops and M52 Desktops using Microsoft Zero-Touch Technology (BDD), *i.e.* the SMS OS deployment feature pack.
- Captured/deployed user profile using USMT.
- Provided deployment end user support for Windows XP, MS Office 2003 and other desktop software.
- Created SMS packages for pre-pilot and pilot rollout.
- Installed and tested SMS packaged applications.
- Assisted in developing plans, strategies and solutions for the design of a new stable and secure desktop, and for the migration of users and services from the current infrastructure into the new design.
- Assisted in identifying detail tasks, schedules and time estimations (effort and duration).
- Assisted in documenting management processes.
- SMS deployment, DNS, DHCP, Printer Management, Server Support.

#### **CIBC**, Montreal

#### Migration Team Leader for Windows Server

May 2006 to July 2006

- Team Leader for Windows 2000 Sever to Windows Server 2003.
- Prepared the environment for deployment of Windows Server 2003.
- Installed, configured, and troubleshoot Windows Server 2003.
- Implemented and managed IP Addressing; configured TCP/IP addressing on a server.
- Used DcDiag, NetDiag techniques for troubleshooting.
- Configured automatic updates for network clients by using Group Policy.
- Designed, planned and implemented Group Policy, delegation strategies and OU structure.

### ABC Limited, Montreal

#### Sr. Technical Support Analyst/Site In-Charge

September 2004 to April 2006

- Managed user accounts, groups, print queues and controlling access rights using Active Directory.
- Responsible for managing Citrix Server 4.0 and configuring Citrix clients.
- Installed, configured, performed troubleshooting and deployed SP1 for Windows 2003 Servers.
- Performed day-to-day administration functions, backup and restoration, file server maintenance.
- Supported all remote offices and home-based users using NetMeeting, VNC and Cisco VPN.
- Created images for various divisions for all desktops and laptops using Ghost.
- Solely responsible for all IT decision making, support and administration at a site of more than 200 'demanding users' in a fast paced architectural and engineering environment.
- Implemented a new in-house printing solution that includes Xerox multi-functional copier, printers, scanners and wide format printer.

### Equifax Canada, Montreal LAN Administrator

September 2003 to September 2004

- Maintained technical knowledge in networking area; operating system (Server and PC).
- LAN Administration: added users; printers; removed users; controlling access right list.
- Monitored server performance.
- Responsible for creating, testing PC images using Image Centre and Ghost.
- Supported more than 250 users at the Equifax Site in Toronto and remote users in Western Canada.
- Backup administration.
- On-Call (24x7).

# Canada Life Insurance, Montreal PC Support Level 3/Project Coordinator for Roll-outs

August 2002 to August 2003

- User Setup Added user I.D.s; set-up printers; Lotus Notes I.D. or Mobile; Internet/Proxy server; data directories; special software, etc.
- Assisted in deploying VPN rollout at Canada Life.
- Provided second level support to Citrix users.
- Provided connectivity (LAN, Internet) troubleshooting and support for approximately 3,500 users.
- Used Asset Insight to keep track of the software installed on the PCs and then use Ghost to create images.
- Responsible for coaching co-op students and new team members.
- Installed and supported PDAs, such as Blackberry® and Palm®.
- Team Leader for the Windows 2000, IBM laptops and desktops rollout.

## National Bank, Montreal IT Support Analyst

March 2002 to August 2002

- Provided technical support for hardware/software configurations and applications.
- Administered and supported local/LAN printers, LAN IDs in Novell.
- Administered/provided troubleshooting for Lotus Notes and MS Outlook.
- Utilized Remedy for call logging.